DJ Scruggs

 $303-808-6614 \cdot me@djscruggs.com$

djscruggs.com linkedin.com/in/djscruggs github.com/djscruggs

A skilled and entrepreneurial software engineer with robust technical expertise and deep experience in client-facing roles for sales, implementation, and support. Proven capability in developing efficient software solutions alongside effective communication and problem-solving.

Skill Summary

React, Node, Remix, Next.js, Ruby on Rails, PHP, JavaScript, TypeScript, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Python, Jupyter Notebook, Git, Docker, Postman, Microsoft Office, GSuite, ActiveCampaign, Hubspot, Zapier, Buildium, Dropbox Sign

Work History

Open-source Projects

October 2023 - present

<u>Automated Penetration Testing Reporting System</u> - a React front-end to a Python API. Uses Vite, Tailwind CSS, Material-Tailwind theme

<u>Trybe</u> - a full stack PWA built in Remix with Prisma/Supabase as back end and Fly.io for deployment

BuiltCities - a full stack React application built on RedwoodJS

BlueSpruce Holdings - Co-founder & Managing Partner June 2017 - October 2023

Led the purchase, management and sale of 330 multifamily apartments. Handled all asset management, finance and investor relations. Implemented the EOS system for business management. Automated our investor communications with ActiveCampaign, Zapier, Buildium, EZ Texting and more.

Chief Technology Officer - Content BLVD

March 2015 - June 2017

Managed the complete product lifecycle for an influencer marketplace. Oversaw strategic planning, resolved tech issues, and delivered a viable product in just 5 months (succeeding when two predecessors failed). Migrated prototype from Moveable Type to use Node and PostgreSQL backend with Mithril/CoffeeScript front end.

Staunch Robots - VP Services

August 2014 - March 2015

Led project management and development for four Ruby on Rails projects.

Avenir International - Chief Technology Officer

January 2014 - August 2014

Led all technical development of a SaaS providing time- and role-based paging for hospital staff to be contacted for urgent critical care tasks. Underlying technology included Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Cisco IP Phones and Twilio.

StatsMix - Chief Technology Officer

October 2010 - January 2013

Led all technical development of a SaaS providing custom analytics integrated with third party reporting tools such as Google Analytics, Mailchimp and dozens of others. Core technology included Ruby on Rails, MySQL, jQuery, Highcharts and more than 30 different web APIs.

SurveyGizmo - VP Sales and Business Development

January 2008 - August 2010

Led sales during explosive growth period from \$130,000 to \$3 million in just two years. Also developed several key platform elements such as SalesForce integration, and entirely re-wrote the billing system. Core technology included PHP, MySQL, Zend Framework and web APIs.

Enthusiast Group – Co-founder

March 2006 - November 2007

Created a B2C social media platform for extreme sports enthusiasts. Core technology included PHP, MySQL, Drupal and JavaScript.

Chief Privacy Officer - MessageMedia

December 1998 - December 2001

Devised and enforced spam-prevention policies for one of the first email marketing companies. Devised and executed a PR and marketing initiative to highlight the company's thought leadership in permission marketing, leading us to win major enterprise accounts such as Cisco Systems and Dell Computer.

Distributed Bits - CEO & Co-Founder

March 1996 - December 1998

Created the industry's first email customer service platform, landing major clients such as Consumer Reports and the Chicago Board Options Exchange. The company was acquired by MessageMedia, providing a 700% return to investors in two years.

Strengths

Leadership: Communication, drive, empathy and accountability move organizations forward.

- As a founder and early employee of multiple companies, I have developed what I call the "comfort of ambiguity." In a changing landscape, I create and iterate on strategic vision while sweating the details to ensure all team members stay on task and deliver.
- As the Managing Partner for BlueSpruce Holdings, I championed and implemented the Entrepreneurial Operating System (EOS) to keep everyone aligned and moving in the right direction. The EOS enabled the company to put on multiple events with hundreds of attendees and build a database of thousands of investors.
- As VP of services for Staunch Robots, I spent a month in Medellin, Colombia to absorb
 the company culture, develop relationships with the developers and establish a
 standard of excellence in service delivery.

Learning: Fast learner across domains with an appetite to meet goals.

- Originally a music major, I taught myself programming and become the CTO of two companies.
- I successfully managed an 83-unit apartment complex with no background in property management.
- While working as a data entry temp at PricewaterhouseCoopers, I taught myself finance and accounting and was hired as a full-time accountant.
- Able to go deep: I have 20 years' experience in SaaS product development, having written more than 500,000 lines of code (PHP, Ruby, JavaScript) and managed teams of engineers with experience ranging from entry level to expert.
- Able to go broad: I have experience in accounting, finance, sales, software development, fundraising, real estate syndication, property management and asset management.

Adaptability: Quickly and effectively adapt to new situations, challenges and environments while maintaining a positive attitude and delivering optimal results.

- I started and joined multiple early-stage startups where the product was in its earliest stages and required continual experimentation and feedback to find product-market fit.
- I took on multiple roles within a company, ranging from CTO to VP of Sales, with a relentless focus on doing whatever it takes for the company's success.

Efficiency: Constantly asking "can we do this faster, cheaper or in fewer steps?"

• At SurveyGizmo (now Alchemer), I saved the company \$50,000+ annually by re-writing the company's payment process and enabling the seamlessly transfer of customers to a lower cost payment processing system.

- Also at SurveyGizmo, I led a series of user focus groups to identify and eliminate areas
 of user confusion and frustration. Small changes led to big improvements in
 conversion rate and customer satisfaction.
- At BlueSpruce Holdings, I built a tightly integrated prospect funnel that used Zapier to link ActiveCampaign, Calendly, SurveyGizmo, SimpleTexting, web APIs and webhooks to automate the capture of necessary information to comply with SEC requirements.
- I implemented technology for the apartment complex to streamline tenant payments, lease applications, electronic leasing, security and reporting to investors. This enabled a full-time job to convert to part time. I also installed security cameras and electronic door locks, removing the need for an onsite security guard.

<u>Impact</u>

Business

- As the VP of Sales at SurveyGizmo, I increased the annual revenue from \$130,000 to \$3M in two years.
- As Chief Privacy Officer at email marketing provider MessageMedia, I pioneered an extremely effective PR initiative to promote privacy as critical to success in email marketing, helping us sign major enterprise clients such as Dell Computer and Cisco Systems.
- As founder and CEO of Distributed Bits, I created the first ever email customer service platform. I sold the company for \$20M, yielding a 700% ROI to investors in three years.
- In a challenging commercial real estate market, I orchestrated a complex sale and lease-option transaction that enabled a property sale at well over market value. This allowed LPs to exit with no loss of principal at a time when 20-30% "haircuts" were common.

Communication and Events

- I built and wrote content for ActiveCampaign's drip marketing campaign to potential investors.
- As an asset manager for a 330-unit real estate portfolio, I handled all communications to investors and prospects, including webinars, monthly email updates, financial reporting, dividend distribution and tax filings.
- I have given dozens of presentations to investors, tech entrepreneurs and real estate operators over the last 20 years (see example here).

Education

Training in Data Science from LinkedIn, Kaggle and other online platforms
Sales Training from Sandler Sales Institute
BS in Music Education, Northwestern University